http://www.onsetcomp.com/corporate/legal/privacy-policy

X
Sorry, we don't support Internet Explorer Version 8 or below. Please consider upgrading your browser, or switching to Chrome or Firefox. Having issues? Contact our web team at webmaster@onsetcomp.com.
COVID-19, effective 11/1/2020
Onset continues to monitor the latest coronavirus developments and guidance from local authorities, the Centers for Disease Control, and the World Health Organization. The health and well-being of our customers, suppliers, employees, and the surrounding community is of the utmost importance to us, so we are taking the necessary precautions to keep everyone safe.
At this time, Onset’s ability to build our products and ship them to our customers as scheduled has not been affected by the coronavirus situation. We are taking proactive measures to work with our suppliers to identify and mitigate any potential supply chain disruptions and will continue to provide updates in the future, as needed.
×
Translate
Happy Holidays - Enter to Win a Free Data Logger!
Onset business statement on COVID-19 impact and response
Company
About OnsetCareersOnset CultureOnset LeanOrdering InformationQuality PolicyNews & EventsEnvironmental FocusOnset SocialOnset AwardsLegal
You are hereHome › Company › Legal
Privacy Policy
Onset Computer Corporation (“Onset”) values our customers, their information, privacy, and trust. This Policy explains how we collect, use, and protect your information through our websites and mobile applications. Specifically, this Policy applies to Onset’s collection, use, storage, and transfer of information associated with Onset’s website, www.onsetcomp.com (the “Site”). If there is something you do not understand about our privacy practices, please feel free to contact us at info@onsetcomp.com.
Throughout this Policy, we refer to the term “Personal Information.” “Personal Information” is data about an individual who can be identified from that data, or by combining it with other data. Personal Information is usually your name in combination with another identifier, such as date of birth, postal address, email address, telephone number, or government-issued identification number. The specific definition of Personal Information varies from one jurisdiction to another.
Personal Information does not include anonymous or aggregated data that can no longer be used to identify a specific person, even if combined with other data.
Many of our customers are businesses, rather than individuals. We do not consider Business Information, such as one’s position, business name, title, business email, business phone number, business address, business fax, and other similar business information, to be Personal Information.
Information We Collect
Information Collected Directly from You
We may collect your name, your company name, your email address, phone number, the type of application you are looking to address with our products or services, and your specific inquiry when you sign up to receive information about our products or services, request a price quote, or voluntarily submit other information to us. We use this information to provide the requested information.
If you wish to chat with one of our service professionals, our partner, Salesforce, will collect your name, business name, business address, and the department you work in at your business in order to identify you and your likely concerns or needs. Salesforce may also retain the contents of your chat indefinitely, in case you have follow-up inquiries and to monitor their services.
If you post information in the Onset user forum, we will collect your username and email address as well as any information you may post in the forum to identify you (in whatever way you choose to be identified) and to provide your information to users of the forum for discussion. Information posted to the forum will be kept for the duration of the forum.
When you report a problem with our Site, product, or services, we will collect your name, email address, phone number, mailing address, the hardware and software at issue, as well as a description of your problem so that we may address it. When you contact us via the company email address, we will collect your email address and any information you include in your email to similarly address your concerns.
We collect your name, phone number, and email address when you purchase products or services through our Site or if you create an account on the Site. For payment processing purposes, we will collect credit or debit card information, but we do not retain this information. We use this information to provide you with your product or service, including confirming your request, ensuring delivery of and payment for your product or service, responding to customer service requests, improving the operation of our application, improving the operation of our Site, conducting research and analysis of how our customers use our Site, and assessing which of our products and services may be of interest to you in the future. We will keep this information for up to twelve (12) months from the date you place your order to allow us to provide you with information about your order. In addition, we may retain Personal Information from past orders where necessary to comply with national laws, prevent fraud, collect any moneys owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our Terms of Use or contractual rights, and take other reasonable actions permitted or required by applicable law.
In the absence of a legal obligation to the contrary, we keep your Personal Information for a year after your last contact with us.
Our Site is not directed to children under age 13 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. Children under 13 should not provide their Personal Information to us through our Site, to customer service, or in writing. If we learn that Personal Information belonging to anyone under the age of 13 is stored on the Site, we will immediately delete such information and refrain from using it for any purpose.
Other Information We Collect
In addition to collecting information directly from you as described in the previous section, we also automatically gather information when you browse or view our Site. This information may include Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and language, internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit websites and applications, operating system, date/time stamp, clickstream data, and other information related to your visit.
We use this browsing information to make sure that the Site and its associated parts are functioning properly, the Site is displayed properly for your equipment and software, and we can provide you with information useful to your location. We also use this information to determine the country or region from which you are visiting to determine what country or region-specific information you see on the Site (e.g., pricing) and to assist in determining whether you are located within a country or region served by one of our distributors (e.g., an “Onset Distributor”).
There are “do not track” or similar browser choices available to internet users with respect to online web activity, but given the present lack of consensus of what constitutes an informed election, appropriate trigger, or breadth of scope of such choice, our Site will not operate any differently when a “do not track” signal is received.
In some of our email messages, you will find a “click-through URL” linked to content on our Site. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click such links in our email messages.
Cookies
We use technologies such as “cookies” so we can remember certain information about you, remember your preferences, or recognize you when you return. Cookies also help us compile aggregate data about Site traffic and Site interaction so that we can improve our Site and protect our Site from fraud.
A cookie is a text file that is stored on your computer. As text files, cookies cannot read information on your hard drive, run programs, or deliver viruses to your computer.
Most browsers are set to accept cookies automatically. You can set your browser to decline all cookies automatically or to prompt you for a response each time a cookie is offered. If you decline cookies, you may find that you cannot access all of our Site’s features.
We use the Pardot Marketing Automation System ("MAS"). MAS is a lead generation and user activity service that uses cookies. These cookies collect data such as your “click path”, or the steps you take to reach the Site. Further information on the purpose,scope and other details of the data collection and its processing by the MAS is available in the privacy policy of Pardot.
During your browsing session, we use “session” cookies to store information and monitor Site function. For thirty minutes after your session, a cookie tracks the number of visitors to our Site.  Until midnight of the day after your last session, a cookie tracks the number of times you visit the Site. For two weeks after your last session, a cookie retains the items you have placed in the Site’s shopping cart, in case you leave without purchasing and then return to make the purchase. There is a permanent cookie used to remember your password.
Web beacons, also known as clear GIFs, are often used in combination with cookies. Often transparent, these images are part of web pages, and allow those who use web beacons to count users who have visited certain pages and to generate statistics about how a website is used. They are not used to access Personal Information. We do not currently use web beacons, but we may do so in the future.
We also use log files when you visit our Site. Log files track IP addresses, browser type, ISP identity, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We utilize this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, prevent fraud, track website navigation in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.
Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they tell those who use pixel tags whether mail has been opened. One use of information obtained from the use of pixel tags is to reduce or eliminate messages sent to customers. We do not currently use pixel tags, but we may do so in the future.
Google AdWords and Google Analytics
We use Google AdWords and Google Analytics in connection with our Site to gather data, such as age, gender, and interests, in order to provide advertising targeted to suit your interests and preferences.
Google Adwords and similar programs from other companies (e.g., Crazy Egg) help us target our online ads based on information collected directly from you or by automated means, like cookies. These companies also use automated technologies to collect information when you click on our ads, which helps track and manage the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.
You may opt out of the automated collection of information by third-party ad networks for the purpose of delivering advertisements tailored to your interests, by visiting the consumer opt-out page for the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising at http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ and edit or opt-out your Google Display Network ads’ preferences at http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/.
Google Analytics collects anonymous information that is not used to identify a particular user. This information helps us better understand how visitors use our Site, detect and defend against fraud and other security risks, and present advertisements, products, and/or services of interest to you.
To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and processes data, please visit “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps”, located at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. To learn about how to opt out of Google Analytics, please visit http://tools.Google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.
Location
You may give consent for our Site to capture and record certain precise geo-location or global positioning data from your device in order to tailor information to your location. We may link such location data to other information that you provide to us or that may be accessed in connection with your use of our Site. You should be able to manage how your mobile device and mobile browser share location information with us, as well as how your mobile browser handles cookies and related technologies, by adjusting your mobile device’s privacy and security settings.
Use of Your Personal Information
We use your Personal Information to further legitimate business interests – to transact business with you and serve you as a customer. As described above, we use your Personal Information to enable you to participate in online transactions, confirm your registration with the Site, send you requested information, administer your account, personalize content so that it applies to you and your interests, compile, analyze, and do research on our user’s demographics and behavior, and detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal. We may also use your Personal Information to communicate with you about products and services we believe you might find of interest and to administer promotions, surveys, contests, and sweepstakes in which you might participate.
We also use the information automatically collected about you during your use of the Site, as described above, to improve the effectiveness of our website, operations, mobile experience, or marketing efforts, or as described elsewhere in this policy, to prevent against fraud and theft, and otherwise to protect our Site’s visitors and our business.
Our employees and agents may view your Personal Information to perform their jobs and service your needs. We authorize access to your Personal Information to them on a need-to-know basis to provide you with our products or services to you, or for one of the other reasons listed in this section.
Sharing Your Personal Information
As a general rule, we will not disclose any of your Personal Information unless we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described in this Policy.
We may share your Personal Information to affiliated companies or others who help us operate the Site or assess your interest or satisfaction with the Site or our products. When we do so, the affiliated company must agree not to use that information for any other reason.
We provide your name and email address to Trustpilot, a vendor we work with to collect reviews of our products and services. We provide the information so that Trustpilot can contact you. The information is not used for any other purpose. And if you wish to opt out of this use, you may opt out of this service by following the directions in the Trustpilot correspondence.
Employment applications go to HRdirect, which collects the information on our behalf, screens the data for relevance, and then passes the information on to us so that we can evaluate your information for consideration for employment. HRdirect retains submitted information indefinitely, subject to our direction. HRdirect has agreed to maintain restrictive account access guidelines in order to only access information if it’s absolutely necessary for customer support, as approved by us.
We may share your Personal Information with the third parties identified in this Privacy Policy who may help us operate the Site or help us assess your interest or satisfaction with the Site.
And we may share your Personal Information with delivery companies or postal companies who we contract with to deliver products you may purchase. In such circumstances, we only provide your name and address to allow for the delivery/postal company to find your delivery location.
We may disclose your Personal Information if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect our operations, clients, or users.
We may release your Personal Information to others (including law enforcement) if we believe such release is reasonably necessary to comply with the law or legal process; enforce or apply the terms of applicable terms of use; detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; or otherwise protect the rights, property, or safety of others.
We may sell, transfer and/or disclose your Personal Information as part of a business divestiture, sale, merger, or acquisition of all or a part of our business. If another company acquires our company, business, or assets, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.  In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, your Personal Information may also be transferred as a business asset.
In addition, we may share aggregate, non-individual information, incapable of identifying a particular person, with third parties for lawful purposes.
If you provide your Personal Information to us. and if we determine you are located within a country or region served by an Onset Distributor, we may provide your Personal Information to an Onset Distributor for follow-up with you regarding our products and services. Onset Distributors may use this information for their own marketing or other purposes, subject to applicable laws.
California Privacy Rights
If you are a California resident, you may have the right to request and receive certain information about a company's disclosure of your personal information to third parties for their own direct marketing use, and your choices with respect to such disclosures. Our Site does not authorize the collection of personal information by third parties except as provided in this Privacy Policy.
If you are a California resident under the age of 18, and a registered user of any site where this policy is posted, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you to request and obtain removal of content or information you have publicly posted. To make such a request, please send an email with a detailed description of the specific content or information to privacy@onsetcomp.com. Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal even if requested.
Links to Other Websites
You may be able to post content to Social Networking sites (such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, and Google+) on which we maintain a presence. If you choose to do this, we will provide information to the Social Networking sites, and receive information from them, in accordance with your elections. You acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for your use of those websites and that it is your responsibility to review the terms of use and privacy policies. We are not responsible for the availability, accuracy, content, products, or services of such Social Network sites.
While you are using the Site, you may be linked or directed to other third-party sites that are beyond our control. Each of these third-party sites may have a privacy policy different from ours.  Please carefully review the privacy policies of these sites. We are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.
Data Movement
We may maintain your Personal Information on computers located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ from those from your jurisdiction.
Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to in connection with a disclosure of Personal Information to Onset Distributors:
We process data, including Personal Information, in the United States. We do not transfer your Personal Information to another organization or a country absent the existence of adequate security and privacy controls. We transfer Personal Information to the United States only with your consent or to perform a contract with you, and consistent with the practices described in this Privacy Policy. We do not collect or store sensitive information about you.
Security Measures
We maintain a variety of industry-standard security measures, including physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards. No system can be completely secure, so we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information, searches, or other communications will always remain secure.
Your Access and Consent to Use of Your Personal Information
If you believe that the Personal Information that we have collected about you is incomplete, inaccurate, or not up to date, or if you would like to review and/or request changes or deletion of that information, you can contact our Data Privacy Officer, using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy.
If you do not consent or want to withdraw your consent for us to collect, use, or disclose your Personal Information as described in this Policy, please contact our Data Privacy Officer using the contact information at the end of this Policy. In your request, please identify the Personal Information at issue and the collection, use, or disclosure you wish to stop.
Denying or withdrawing consent may not allow us to provide you with some or all of the products, services, or information you request.
You may opt out of receiving marketing-related emails by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any email you receive from us. If you are having difficulty unsubscribing from our marketing communications, please contact us at (508) 759-9500.
If you opt out from receiving marketing emails or text messages, we may still need to send you communications about your orders, customer service inquiries, and other matters.
If you agreed to receive future marketing communications directly from a third party through our Site, you will need to contact that party to opt out of such communications. This process may be outlined on that party's privacy policy.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the Site and we will change the “Last Modified” date below.
Questions and Contact Information
If you have any questions or need additional information you may contact our Data Privacy Officer at:
privacy@onsetcomp.com
Last Modified: February 8, 2019
Contact Us
1-508-759-9500 (U.S. and International)
1-800-LOGGERS (U.S. only)
1-800-564-4377 (U.S. only)
Sales/Customer Service
Technical Support
Find a Distributor
Onset Computer Corporation
470 MacArthur Blvd.
Bourne, MA 02532
About Onset
About Onset
Careers
Company Video
Legal
Privacy Policy
News & Events
Trustpilot
Onset®, HOBO®, InTemp®, HOBOnet®, HOBOlink®, HOBOmobile®, HOBOware®,
HOBOconnect™, Pendant®, TidbiT®, FlexSmart™, and all other names of Onset products referenced herein are trademarks or registered trademarks of Onset Computer Corporation. ®1995-2020 Onset Computer Corporation.
All rights reserved.
WaterPopularWater Monitoring SolutionsWater Level SolutionsWater Quality SolutionsNEW! HOBO MicroRX Water Level StationResourcesAll Water ResourcesUse CasesApplication StoriesHow-To VideosSelf-Guided TrainingWebinarsWhite PapersSoftware & AccessoriesHOBOwareHOBOmobileHOBOconnectHOBOlinkAccessoriesMeasurementsConductivityDissolved OxygenpHTemperatureWater Level/FlowAll Water ProductsOutdoorPopularOutdoor Monitoring SolutionsWeather StationsWireless Sensor NetworkSoil ConditionsNEW! HOBO MicroRX StationResourcesAll Outdoor ResourcesUse CasesApplication StoriesHow-To VideosSelf-Guided TrainingWhite PapersSoftware & AccessoriesHOBOwareHOBOmobileHOBOconnectHOBOlinkAccessoriesMeasurementsBarometric PressureEvapotranspirationLeaf WetnessLight IntensityOther4-20 mA SensorsDC VoltageDew PointEventsPulse InputSnow DepthTilt / AccelerationRainfallRelative HumiditySoil Electrical ConductivitySoil MoistureSoil TemperatureTemperatureWindAll Outdoor ProductsIndoor & HVACPopularIndoor Monitoring SolutionsAir Quality MeasurementsEnergy AuditingHVAC MonitoringNEW! Remote Monitoring SolutionsNEW! MX Analog Multi-Channel Data LoggersNEW! MX Gateway for cloud-based dataResourcesWhite PapersAll Indoor ResourcesUse CasesApplication StoriesHow-To VideosSelf-Guided TrainingWebinarsSoftware & AccessoriesAccessoriesHOBOwareHOBOmobileHOBOconnectHOBOlinkMeasurementsEnergyPower FactorAC CurrentAC VoltageDC CurrentDC VoltageKilowatt HoursPlug LoadIndoor Air QualityCarbon DioxideOther4-20 mA SensorsAir VelocityCompressed Air FlowDC VoltageDew PointLight IntensityPulseWater FlowPressureGauge PressueDifferential PressureRelative HumidityTemperatureThermocoupleTime of UseLight on/offMotor on/offOccupancyRuntimeState open/closeAll Indoor ProductsVaccines & Cold ChainPopularLife SciencesBlood & PlasmaTransportationStorageClinical TrialsHealth CareHospitals, Clinics, and PharmaciesVaccines for ChildrenRecalibration ProgramResourcesNews & EventsResourcesSoftwareInTemp Mobile AppInTemp Connect Cloud SoftwareProductsCX GatewayStorage LoggersAmbient TemperatureCryogenic, Single UseCryogenic, Multiple UseDry Ice, Single UseDry Ice, Multiple UseTemperature/RHTemperature (Glycol)Temperature (Probe)Transportation LoggersCryogenic, Single UseCryogenic, Multiple UseDry Ice, Single UseDry Ice, Multiple UseTemp 90-Day, Single UseTemp 365-Day, Multiple UseTemperature/RHVFC Temperature (with Glycol)ApplicationsAll ApplicationsAgricultural MonitoringAgricultureAgricultural ResearchCold Chain MonitoringLife SciencesBlood & PlasmaTransportationStorageClinical TrialsHealth CareVaccines for ChildrenHospitals, Clinics, and PharmaciesEnvironmental MonitoringEnvironmental ResearchGreen Roof MonitoringIndoor MonitoringPreservation ManagementAir Quality MonitoringEnergy AuditingHVAC System MonitoringWater MonitoringCoastal EcologyHydrology StudiesWater QualityResourcesAll ResourcesUse CasesApplication StoriesKnowledge BaseUser ForumProduct LibraryVideosWebinars & CoursesWhite PapersCompanyAbout OnsetBlogCareersContact UsNews & Events
